Hello, I'm Sifu Mallon with the Clearwater Kung Fu center.
This is my assistant Melissa, and this is kick boxing.
We're working on pad drills today.
The pad drill that we're going to begin with is our uppercut drill.
OK, this one is a stationary drill.
OK just going through the action with it.
I'll start with my feet shoulder width apart.
I'll twist to my left, OK twist to my left, and I'll fire my left hand up.
Boom.
I bring my left hand to body, my left, right hand drops down, fire to right.
Again with this, I'm staying stationary, right, but I'm still on my hips, and my legs can move in the side to side action.
As I'm pushing from one side to the other, I don't want to straighten my leg completely up, but I do want to push a little bit up.
Up, up, has this nice twisting action.
OK Melissa let's go ahead and come forward.
And we'll do the pad drill with each other.
So we start with our feet shoulder width apart.
OK our hands are up, right, I'm putting a little bit back.
OK, now to start the action, she's going to turn in this way slightly, she's going to allow this hand to kind of roll down a little bit, and then fire up.
Good.
Now, once she makes contact with the pad, she's going to left it up here, and then the hand is going to come straight back, not loop up, but straight back to her this way.
And then she's going to fire the other hand straight up and pull it straight in.
Now she wants to use the body, you want to dip the hand a little lower before you punch out, that's it.
And I'm looking for the center.
And meeting that hand each time.
That's it.
Good, relax.
Again, my elbows are into the body this way, and I'm working the technique, boom, this way, this way, keeping my elbows nice and tight.
For the punch, you're performing the uppercuts, we want to remember to twist a little, drop the hand a little low, like rotating it, and fire up.
The hand comes straight back this way, the left hand drops down, I use the twist this way.
So there's a nice counter action with your body, so there's a lot of body mechanics going on in these basic drills.
This is basic drill combos, kick boxing.